#大家好 今左我看一下兄弟家的杮子有沒有熟哦
Hi everyone! Today I come to see if my buddy's persimmons are ready.
#在這 杮子樹
It's here, the persimmon tree.
#好多青的
Many are still green.
#哇 這邊黃了哦
Wa! Those on this side have turned yellow.
#那麼多哦 剛好我叫了我弟過來 叫了他們幫忙
There are a lot! Good that I have asked my younger brother to come with me. He can help.
#哇 這棵樹 這棵樹好黃了已經
Wa! This tree, this tree is already yellow everywhere.
#好從這裡上去
I climb from here.
#行不行哦這個
Can I make it?
#這棵樹太好了這棵樹 那麼多樹枝
This tree is nice. It has so many branches.
#哇 好多黃的哦
Wa! A lot of yellow persimmons.
#來 拿叉子給我 (註︰那是一把剪刀，不是叉，我想他只是隨便叫些甚麼而已經，所以譯作Stuff算了)
Come on! Give me that stuff.
#接著 接著
Catch it! Catch it!
#可以放沒有
Are you ready?
#啊放
Ah, ya!
#就摘了那麼一點點
So we've just a little bit here.
#這些都爆了
There are cracked,
#摔爆了
when they hit the ground.
#哇 這個 這個可以吃的這個
Wa! This, this can be eaten.
#我們這邊叫油杮子
It's called "you bizi" (lit: oil persimmon) here.
#好多肉啊
It's so rich.
#這果肉
The pulp...
#你看 這個 熟了 這個
Look! This is, ready, ready now.
#哎呀 這個不是很熟
Aya! Not really.
#但是味道已經可以啦
But the taste is already not bad.
#很有那個杮子味哦
It's very flavourful.
#這些放一段時間才可以吃哦 這個
These persimmons need to be ripened for a period of time before they can be eaten.
#先把它
First let me,
#放到袋子上去
put them into the bag.
#讓我們帶回家裡去吃
So that we can enjoy at home.
#在這裡吃了太多啦
I've eaten too much here.
#等下兄弟過來啦就不好
It would be too bad if my buddy came here now.
#不好辦 (註︰其實不太知道這個「不好辦」是指兄弟過來便不好辦，還是杮子很難處理，但前者較有趣)
Too bad.
#這個 摘了那麼一點點
So you see, we've got just a bit here.
#這個又不熟
And this is not too ready.
#好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡了
Alright! The video ends here.
#都不是很熟
They're not really too ready.
#下次過來 下次過來摘
Let's come again, come again later.